# **Arpit Solanki**

I have experience with data, infrastructure, backends, and managing projects like <u>DISHA</u>. I have worked with data cataloging, versioning, workflow orchestration, data ingestion, efficient data storage, monitoring infrastructure, on-premise deployment, writing backends, one to one mentoring/teaching.

#### **Technical Skills**

Likes:

python airflow prestodb hive dask apache-spark parquet workflow docker data-ingestion rabbitmq linux prometheus git

#### **Experience**

## Data Engineer - SocialCops

Jun 2018 → Current

airflow, prestodb, parquet, apache-spark, dask, hive, monitoring, prometheus, rabbitmq, docker

- Worked on deployments and development for the project DISHA
- Worked on data cataloging using Presto as a query engine and Hive as metastore.
- · Worked on automated data reports to help data scientists and business users see how is data.
- · Worked on a simple versioning system for data to keep track of changes in data.

#### Mentor - Codementor

Jan 2019 → Mar 2019

python, workflow, github, apache-spark, api

- Provide one to one live help on given problems/bugs to mentees
- · Teach and guide on new technologies, fields or approaches on problem-solving.
- Have done over 100 sessions with people with 5 star rating.

## Data Engineering Intern - SocialCops

Jan 2018 → May 2018

python, celery, deployment, web-scraping, data-ingestion, workflow, airflow

- Worked on deployments and development for the project <u>DISHA</u>.
- Worked on data ingestion through APIs, databases, Object stores etc.
- Worked on ETL pipelines and workflow management with Airflow

#### Backend Developer Intern - Vstv.io

Sep 2017 → Nov 2017

 $node. js, \ express, \ mongodb, \ jwt, \ bcrypt, \ video-streaming, \ video-capture$ 

I am working as a Backend developer intern with MEAN stack. My responsibilities includes creating web services, handling data streams to Backend and collaboration with frontend team.

#### **Backend Developer** - MateLabs

May 2017 → Jul 2017

python-2.7, django, django-rest-framework, orm, ifttt, postgresql, amazon-ec2, amazon-s3, boto3, docker, rabbitmq, celery, diango-celery, luigi

Creating web services in Django, Integrating machine learning and deep learning pipelines, Improve Mateverse back end.

Full Stack Developer and Code Reviewer (Remote) – <u>BrainPlay Learning Solutions</u> node.js, express, mongodb, rest, pm2, mocha, chai

May 2017  $\rightarrow$  Jul 2017

Database designs and optimisation, Testing functionality of rest-apis, finding possible bugs.

## Education

B.Tech – Indian Institute of Information Technology Vadodara

Aug 2014 → Apr 2018

### **Human Detection and Tracking**

In this Project we have worked on the problem of detecting and recognizing a human in a video which can be useful in surveillance systems and security applications.

#### **MobileCloudIR**

MobileCloudIR is a distributed system which stores the whole Wikipedia dump in different smartphones. Users can query and get related articles. This system includes an Android application and a coordinator web server running in the local network

Projects & Interests	Stack Overflow – https://stackoverflow.com/users/5250746/arpit-solanki	Aug 2015 → Current
	Written 238 answers. Active in django, python, django-templates, node.js, python-3.x and 3 other tags.	
Public Artifacts	<b>Testing Celery Tasks – Arpit Solanki – Medium</b> – https://medium.com/@solankiarpit1997/testing-cele a8a3568d0213 python, celery, task, scheduled-tasks	ery-tasks- Feb 2018
	Recently I came across the problem of writing unit tests for Celery tasks. Writing unit tests for celery tasks since they	ks can be painful
Apps & Software	PQusic – http://github.com/arpit1997/pqusic python-3.4, django, beautifulsoup, html5, css3, plyr, html5-audio, javascript, jquery, materializecss	Dec 2016
	A music web application	
	Won 2nd prize at Hackathon-2016 IIIT Vadodara – Acomplishment	Mar 2016

SyncIt is a cross-platform client to synchronize work with your Google Drive folder specifically targeting public PC's